Computer Science Graduate | SDE - II @ W.W.Grainger

Ambitious and dedicated professional with experience in the software industry. Demonstrated success in problem solving, solution development and a track record with strong attention to detail.

Education

- Master of Science, Computer Science (Graduated in May 2017), University of Illinois, Chicago. GPA: 3.78/4.
- Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science, SRM University, India. GPA: 8.17/10.

Technical Expertise

- Programming Languages: Golang, JavaScript, Python and Ruby.
- · Web Development: HTML 5, CSS3, JavaScript, NodeJS, AngularJS, JQuery, ReactJS, Express Js, Ruby on Rails and PHP.

Interpersonal skills:

- Self-motivated | Strong work ethic | Problem solving attitude | Open to constructive feedback.
- Team player | Experience working in teams with diverse backgrounds and experiences.

Work Experience

W.W. Grainger, Chicago | SDE - II

(July 2018 - Present)

- Part of the engineering team that is working on writing a separate service for order validation.
- Study the current hybris system and architecture to replace it with a microservice.
- · Worked on implementing POCs to study different designs.
- · Technical expertise gained: GoLang

Gamut Supply - A Grainger company, Chicago | Platform Engineer

(November 2017 - July 2018)

- · Member of the engineering team that develops and maintains the technology infrastructure for the company.
- Develop and maintain platforms for supporting the website for the company.
- · Develop and maintain the internal customer service platforms.
- · Redesign and refactor the existing platforms to make it highly scalable.
- Technical expertise gained: Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, ReactJs, NodeJS, Javascript, Postgres SQL and MongoDB.

W.W. Grainger, Chicago | Innovation Intern (May 2016-Apr 2017) | Technical Product Associate (June 2017 - November 2017)

- · Developed chart features for historical data on reordered items in an existing reorder tablet project.
- · Redesigned and developed a reorder button system using NodeJS and MongoDb.
- · Developed a tool to allow customers find instant product availability information by a text message.
- · Redesigned and developed the software part of a smart vending machine.
- · Migrated a parse server to a custom in-house server.
- · Data analysis to explore trends in customer behaviors.
- · Technical expertise gained: NodeJS, MongoDb, Express Js, AngularJS, Handlebar view engine and UI/UX skills, Python.

Tata Consultancy Services, India | Assistant Software Engineer

(Aug 2014-June 2015)

- · Worked on the retail field for the South African retail giant Woolworths in Oracle 11G forms and PL/SQL platforms.
- Developed and migrated oracle forms from 8i to 11g for customer requirements and handled datasets using PL/SQL.

NEWGEN Knowledge Works, India | Project Intern

(July 2012-August 2012)

 \cdot Involved with the R&D team to develop a tool for converting a book in word format to the Epub format.

Other Project Experiences

Visualization and Visual Analytics - "Moments in History":

- · Analyzing US population data with reference to certain historical events.
- · Expertise gained: D3 library in JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

Visualization and Visual Analytics - "Shadows in the Rain":

- · A web application to visualize the path of hurricanes over the Atlantic and Pacific oceans over the years.
- Involved with setting up the database, wrote Sql queries to clean & fetch data for graphs and other modules, and prepared the PHP files to fetch data from back-end.

Visualization and Visual Analytics - "Rave On"

- · A web application enabling two users to compare their music tastes and visualizes data on artists and genres.
- · Expertise gained: UI/UX skills with other web technologies.
- · Involved in setting up static data points, fetched data from the echonest API for each feature, set up artists' information on the map and fetched data dynamically for each feature on the timeline, Force Directed Graph and the map.

Achievements:

· Awarded the Amadeus' Best use of Amadeus API award in HackIllinois 2016 conducted at UIUC.